### **VENKATESH NALLA**

### Front End Web Developer

1160 St Mathieu, Montreal, Quebec, Cell-+1-514-217-3435,

Email – <u>venkateshnalla94@gmail.com</u>, GitHub - <u>https://github.com/venkateshnalla94</u> Portfolio-<u>https://venkateshnalla94.github.io</u>

# **Summary**

Web Developer with experience around two years in Designing interactive, responsive web applications, layouts and real-time rendering of data in JavaScript. Strong creative and analytical skills in functional programming. Team player with utmost importance to design requirements.

JavaScript ES6, ReactJS, Bootstrap, Material UI, CSS and Java.

# Experience

# Cino/ Web Developer /July 2018-October 2019

Worked on developing the Inventory system for the Inhouse application on user actions in ReactJS. Real-time rendering of the data based on API calls by Asynchronous programming. Significantly reduced the server request by minification of JavaScript and CSS calls to the server.

## Responsibilities.

- Developed the application to have Cross browser Compatibility.
- Frameworks like Bootstrap and Material UI are implemented for Responsive Web design.
- Designed Layout of the application in CSS grids to reduce the complexity of the design.
- Asynchronous programming by calls to API using Fetch and Axios es6.

#### SSTech /Intern/June 2019-December 2016

Improving the granularity of the source code and raise the test coverage of the product by creating JUnit test-cases. Raise of cohesion in the design, debugging and ensuring the correctness is under optimum levels.

### **Responsibilities**

- Creation of Static Websites in Jekyll using HTML and CSS.
- Code refactoring and functional programming to increase code reusage
- Achieving 75 % optimal test coverage by creating Junit test cases.

## **Projects**

### Twitter Analytics/December 2017-April 2018

Developed an application that involves functionality to produce the tweets based on the keyword search algorithm in actors-based programming. Implemented the design with the help of twitter4J API to get and post data.

## **Responsibilities**

- Test Driven Development approach to cover and ensure the correctness of the code.
- Documented the application in JACOCO.
- Version control and collaborative work using GitHub.
- Made the design responsive using Twitter Bootstrap and media queries.

# Schedule Builder / September 2018 to January 2019

Built a design for Student schedule builder with design constraints involved using the Iterator, Facade design patterns and created a scope for the system to evolve by slashing out the coupling and raising the cohesion.

### Responsibilities

- Developed pseudo-code for better understandable documentation.
- Functional based programming approach to refactor and minification purpose.
- Implemented the code in Eclipse.

### Complexity Estimator/ April 2017 to July 2017

Created a class to find the mean, variance to a set of random numbers generated by using inbuilt functions and estimate the complexity involved in the code hierarchy using Complexity meter and brought back it to optimum levels (level 7).

# Responsibilities

- Code base in Java to perform unit testing on functional components.
- Used Metriculator to determine and hence control the cyclo metric complexity involved.
- Refactoring of programme to improve the performance by minimizing the memory usage.

#### **Skills**

- Programming languages -JavaScript, ReactJs, Java.
- Markup and Design -HTML & CSS.
- Frameworks -React, Bootstrap, Material UI, CSS grids
- Library and Data Fetching-jQuery and Fetch, Axios.

#### Education

Master's - Concordia University, Montreal.

Majors-Computer Science.

Bachelors – JNTU Kakinada, India.

Majors – Electrical & Electronics Engineering